[Music]
Heat. Heat.
Heat. Hey, heat. Hey, heat.
[Music]
Good evening, good day, namaste
everybody and welcome to the
254th episode live episode of the Ask
Abij show. I hope you're all doing
fantastic. It's great to see you all. I
can see a lot of you already on the live
chat. So, thank you so much for being
here. I will take as many questions of
yours as possible over the next hour or
so. But before I start, let me see who
all is there on the live stream. I can
see Shri Ram Chundraa, Mr. Adoras, Pujan
Patel, Mr. Reactors Zone GK, Dilling Pu
from Assam, Namaste, Pravin SS, uh Event
Countdown, Anand Chandak, Mr. Jam
Priyanchi Sud Om uh Info King Kumar
Kanesh Yashwant Sudir uh NTN88 Samraati
Kumar Kaneshk Vinayman Geopolitical Dub
from Indor Chil Yash channel Mr. Biz
Kumar Kanesh Kagan Akash Sharma Sudhakar
S Rahul Dunak who else do we have Akila
Narayan uh Vijitraati pane Paul from
Kolkata my good friend Anand
Chandakwant
Sudir Sarup Exim Nimish Gupta
Adit07
Xenomorphosis Susant Das Pranayumar
Rajat Agarwal Darya Bhanavat Deepika
Arian Musk Priyanka Jaw Alia, Samim,
Sury, Pawan, Air Gandhi, Hari, Chan,
Gul, Vikas, PJ, Somi, Jade, Abishek,
Shivas, Karan, Nalawat, Juram, Hunter,
Kenway. Who else do we have? P, PDR,
Mastan blogs, Vinayan, Arian, Patel,
Nuro, Arnav, Son, Pankage, Giki, Nikil,
Bansali, sir, SC, Mystic,
uh, and and so many other people. for
Ankita, Somi, Jen and and so many so
many other people. So, thank you so much
for being on the live stream. Welcome
everybody and let me take as many
questions as possible. I will take uh
the live chat questions obviously on a
priority basis. Let's do that. Let's go
with question number one. Kumar Kanesh
says, "Can it can it be possible that
the UFOs we hear about are actually
humans for the from the future or more
like time travelers and the UFOs are
their time machines on a research
mission?"
Well, it's not entirely 100% impossible.
There is a small probability that that
that could be the case, but uh there is
nothing in well, according to the laws
of physics, time travel is theoretically
kind of possible if you do some
manipulation of of space-time conditions
using Ein field equations. Essentially,
it's allowed by the field equations of
Einstein, if you use wormholes and long
distances and stuff like that. But have
we ever seen evidence of time travelers
ever? I mean, look, if if UFOs are the
vehicles of time travelers, then why
don't they come down here and talk to us
and and tell us how the future is like,
right? What what
what time period are you coming from and
how are things then then? What's the
technology we have in in the future and
so on. So, uh I think the chance is very
low. I'm sure it's not entirely zero.
Maybe they have a miss research mission.
Maybe they they want to study us from
far away. Maybe that that was the case.
It could be the case
perhaps. NTN88 says, "Who do you think
gave Zilinski authority to do such an
audacious attack? Do you think Trump
didn't know about the attack?" I think
it looks like Mr. Trump was not aware of
the attack at all. The uh Operation
Spiderweb attack on Russian airfields
and the Kirchbridge attack. It doesn't
look like Mr. Trump was aware of this at
all. He was completely silent about this
for about 48
hours. Looks like Mr. Trump was
completely caught off guard. And if that
is the case, I think he only has himself
to blame, Mr. Trump. Um, he did not take
Mr. Zalinsky seriously. And Mr. Zilinsky
is now showing to Mr. Trump,
demonstrating that look, I have the
cards. I have many cards up my sleeve.
The cards that you are asking about, the
cards you were speaking about in the in
the old office. Let me show you the
cards. Here is card number one.
Spiderweb. Here's card number two.
Kirchbridge card number three, train
attacks. Now, let's see what other cards
he has. I don't think anybody has given
Zilinski the attack, the the audacity or
the or the authority to do this O
audacious attack. I think he is now
battleh hardened. Initially, he was a
comedian. Now he's he's transforming
into a Ukrainian Wilson Church, it looks
like. H So, I don't think Trump was
aware of this. Zalinski has taken charge
it looks like and maybe he is supported
by the European nations the the the EU
nations or NATO nations without the US
involvement. So that's what it looks
like is happening over
here. Ud the Bhav Sharma says if the USA
and Indian deep states are not aligned
with the national interest, how can
ordinary people like us replace them and
do the needful especially overcoming the
corruption and coged system
here. India doesn't have a deep state.
India has some uh powerful people who
have been powerful because of their
their ancestors status as British era
elites. Um I'm not sure. Yeah. But
whoever they are whoever they may be
probably aren't aligned with our
national interest. The US deep state
well the US deep state is is it owns the
US if it does exist. How can ordinary
people like us replace the deep state
and do the needful? Ordinary people like
us cannot replace the deep state and do
with the neutral. First of all, we don't
even know who they are. And we don't
know what their means of control of
power are. See that one thing the the
Anglo-Saxons have done is they have very
craftily hidden away from public sight.
They're instruments of power.
Historically, everybody would
demonstrate the instruments of power.
See why we are so great. We have this
and that and whatever. The Anglo-Saxons
have very craftily hidden away the
instruments of power and hidden away
where the real power centers lie. So
it's impossible to find where they are
apparently. So how do we replace them? I
mean if you want to replace them you
have to become become powerful. How do
you become more powerful? How can an
ordinary person be become
powerful? What is power then? Then the
question is what is power? Like Maung
said power flows from the barrel of a
gun. Right? Influence is not power.
Power is power. Power means you have an
army of people who will obey you without
question and who will do whatever you
say. That's power. That's a force
multiplier. That's leverage. How can
ordinary people do that? Unless you get
deep into things and get into politics
or something. Otherwise, you can't.
Otherwise, you
can't. Udb says, "Can you please
recommend top books you believe are
necessary for becoming highly
successful, wealthy, powerful, tax
techsavvy in today's world? Mix of
genres, technology, mindset,
et I have always been so loath to do
book recommendations. See, how do you
become successful? What's the book for
becoming successful? Is it a set of
books? I I don't really do self-help
books. Successful. What about books
about strategy, etc.? If you want to
understand power, if you want want to
understand strategy
etc. You got to read books like for
example well if you want to understand
amoral strategy in power you can uh read
books by
Brzinski Bzinski I'm sure I have a few
up here you can read books by uh Henrik
Kissinger
diplomacy what
else one is diplomacy the other is
leadership
um so that that is all about aoral
power grabs and stuff. I mean, not about
power grabs as such, but that's how the
how the really the world works. Books
about becoming wealthy. I don't know
books about maybe you should read
uh uh what was his
name. Can't remember the guy's name.
There was this uh British entrepreneur
uh Felix Dennis who wrote a book about
how to become rich or something. Maybe
it's a good book. Maybe it's a good I
think I read it like 15 years ago or 20
years ago. Uh and so on. TechSavvy, you
can't read books to become techsavvy.
You have to get your hands dirty with
technology. You have to dive deep into
technology and actually start using it,
creating it, modifying it. That's how
you become techsavvy. You don't become
techsavvy by reading books. You don't
become wealthy also by reading books.
You become wealthy by taking risks,
financial risks and calculated risks,
not reckless risks. And similarly it
goes to becoming powerful.
So Sachin thank you very much sir. Thank
you. Sterk Bay says with the US national
debt crossing 36 trillion what are the
possible long-term global risks? Could
this lead to major economic or
geopolitical shifts? Look, as long as
the US is in control, it it it has the
world's best power positioning
capabilities and it has it controls more
than 700 extr territorial military
bases. I don't think nothing will I
don't think anything will happen to the
US dollar's hegemony. So the US dollar
is is based on US American global
military power projection and their
ability to intervene militarily anywhere
on the globe at 60 minutes roughly
notice. So it doesn't matter how much
their n national debt crosses. So what
they're
doing what is what exactly is the US
national
debt it means that they are selling
pieces of paper to other
countries who are so you you sell
sovereign bonds to countries and you and
the country gives you dollars back in
return. That's the kind of scam it is.
The sovereign bond is is a promise that
I'll pay you back with US dollars again.
It's a complete scammy system, complete
circular logic and so on. But
since the debt is in US dollars, all the
US has to do is to print a little bit
more dollars and give it back. See,
here's the difference. If India owes
let's say a billion dollars to another
country and we have to pay it back. Hm.
We have to first earn those billion
dollars by trading with other countries
by giving those countries actual
goods. That's how we earn the paper $1
billion and that's how we pay the debt
back. If the US owes somebody a billion
dollars, they'll just print the billion
dollars and give it give the money. So
that's that's the entire financial
system global financial system is is
based on it's it's the foundation is is
this scam. So the risks are
significant. Uh right now nobody's going
to dare to ask the US uh even the
Chinese own trillions of dollars of US
securities. It doesn't make any
difference. And if the Chinese ask the
Americans to pay it back, the Americans
may even refuse. So overall the entire
system is a scam. And the global risk
long-term risk is that eventually this
will collapse. when it collapses the
entire global financial system will
collapse which means that nations won't
be able to trade with with each other
very
easily. Um so it could cause genuine
massive global economic shifts and that
comes with geopolitical shifts
also. Diva Sharma says Vietnam,
Indonesia, Singapore, Israel sovereign
or not? The only fully sovereign nations
in the world 100% sovereign are the US,
Russia, China, India and Israel, five
nations. Uh other nations have their
sovereignty that is compromised in a
various ways, a variety of ways. So
Vietnam not 100% sovereign sadly. I
would love it to be so sovereign. It's a
beautiful nation. Indonesia wonderful
nations.
Singapore
no. Okay. Jagen says s world bank is
going to give $40 billion to Pakistan.
Yes, I gave a detailed presentation
about this
yesterday. $40 billion 50% to the
government and 50% to the private
sector 20 billion to the government 20
billion to the private sector. That's
what the World Bank is going to do over
the next 10 years to Pakistan. So will
Pakistan come back stronger whenever
clashes with India? Why our forces on
regular basis strike across border
inside terrorist
facilities? Pakistan will remain afloat.
The US and its various assets like the
World Bank, the IMF etc. They're going
to keep Pakistan aloat because they need
Pakistan Pakistan is a very major
valuable asset for the US to keep India
counterbalance off balance to keep on
you know needling India and poking India
whenever required. Pakistan is very
valuable to the US. The Americans will
not allow Pakistan to go under. Without
all this aid, Pakistan would have
collapsed a long long long time ago. So
Pakistan will survive. Pakistan will
continue to exist. Maybe they'll come
back stronger if the Americans give
sufficient money. But they don't want
Pakistan to become too strong either.
They just want to keep it the way it is.
You see? So why do our forces on regular
basis strike across border into inside
terror terror facilities? Because we are
not a nation that strikes at civilians.
We don't target civilians. We will
strike at terror facilities and we will
target strike at terror camps and bases
and if required we'll st we'll strike at
Pakistani military infrastructure and
targets not
civilians. Um and we wish that we do not
have to do this. We wish Pakistan would
mind its own business and we would not
have to do all this. But they force us
to do it by constantly indulging in
terrorism and exporting terrorism to
India. Akash says is it possible for the
PM of BAT to create a secret commando
group which can eliminate the 0.5 front
hidden force including international
politicians. It's look I'm not
recommending anything like this but
anything is possible.
Kumar Kanesh says to deal with Pakistan
conventionally can we make WMD silently
like country I as option to escalate
like 71B possible without west war
interference to deal with Pakistan
conventionally can we had make WMD
silently like country I as option to
escalate like 71B possible without I'm
not sure what you're asking sir I
usually understand
things. Weapons of mass destruction.
What are Okay, let me talk about WMDs.
Weapons of mass
destruction. Weapons of mass destruction
are either nuclear weapons or chemical
weapons or biological weapons. We don't
do nuclear we don't do chemical. We
don't do biological. That's that's
crimes against humanity. The only thing
we do is nuclear. We have a nuclear
stockpile. So, we have a nuclear
stockpile. We don't need to be silent
about it. It's pretty open.
Um and can something be possible without
western war interference? No. The moment
we strike at Pakistan, the west will
interfere. Guaranteed. Guaranteed. But
the point about nuclear weapons is that
we don't want to use them ever. It's for
deterrence. Mr. Bisby says, "Oh, thank
you, sir. Thank you very much. Very nice
of you." Mr. Bisby again. How is it that
we still have really bright-minded
individuals in spite of the bright bad
education system? How do we become like
them? like whom
bright-minded uh first of all why do we
have bright-minded individuals despite
the horrible education system because
talent will will somehow find a
way Ramanojun found a way right despite
the horrific education system which
nearly nearly destroyed him but he found
a way he was determined he reached out
and Hardy found him he reached out to
Hardy and Hardy Hardy saw that this
guy's a goddamn genius
um so look India is a nation of immense
talent. We have the brightest people in
the world and they they succeed because
of their deter determination. They
succeed because of the talent, their
hard work and for many of them the
education system no matter how garbage-l
like it is, it doesn't stop
them. So we have the brightest people in
the world. No question. So the education
system can only seek to u you know slow
them down but as long as they have
determination they can't be stopped. How
do we become like them? by working as
hard as possible and being super
optimistic.
Nikil
says best book to teach best books to
teach in Indian violence to a baby girl
who's just 1.5 year old any
lectures I think at the age of 1.5 years
I'm not sure anybody can read a book uh
but I'm sure you can read a book to them
you know read it aloud or something the
best book for Indian values are the good
old books the Mahabharat draman right
maybe the oponyishads but the question
is can a 1.5year-old handle that uh
maybe you can wait for a few years until
she is uh maybe five six years old at
that time the Mahabharat Ramayan become
really interesting as long as you teach
as long as you communicate it at the
level of a kid you know so I think the
best books for Indian values are the
mahabharat ramayan opishadas the vedas
all of this and the opishations vedas
etc are all pretty complicated for most
people so stick to the maharad and
ramayan and of course there is the jatak
katas the jatak tales
the punch tantra all of that is great
for kids. So these are some of the best
things you can
do.
Um Rohan says how would you create
vasals for India as a
PM? How would you create vasals for
India as a PM? By being more powerful by
becoming more powerful. Right now India
is not in the position to create more
vasals. only by being more powerful
being at least a $10 trillion economy
with the corresponding military might
then you can think of creating missiles
really now says I am thoroughly scared
we must strike preemptively you mean
about the asymmetric threat from
Pakistan no point being scared the
government will do what's needed
technological capabilities are superb of
course it's going to be a challenge
after we saw what the Ukrainians did to
Russia yeah so we we cannot be
complacent
But I'm sure we'll be fine. We have more
threats now. The Pakistanis will will
try some nonsense. I'm sure sooner or
later. They have always done that. So,
we're going to have to be ready. But
let's not be thoroughly scared. Let's be
positive and optimistic. Anish, thank
you very much, sir. Djamat, thank you
sir. Pakistan got a temporary position
at the UN Security Council in a
supposedly influential position. Is this
a diplomatic victory for them which can
unfortunately be used to prevent the
continuation of operation
sindur? This uh temporary
position cannot be used to prevent the
resumption of operation sindur if we
choose to resume it. Just because you
have a certain statusdriven position
doesn't make you
powerful. But yeah, this is a reward for
Pakistan of some kind from the US or
maybe from China, maybe from both. See
both the US and China see eye to eye on
on Pakistan. China doesn't want India to
rise to grow much. So Pakistan is very
valuable in that regard. Pakistan can
keep India off balance. The US also
doesn't seek doesn't want India to
become the next China in a in a by a
2040 horizon time horizon. So they also
want Pakistan to continue to exist. So
to have Pakistan continue continue to
exist. They they want to take the
world's eyes off Pak both nations US and
China don't want the world world to
regard Pakistan as a terrorist nation.
They want to whitewash the image of
Pakistan. So American the American
military Afric commander recently said
that the Sahel region is the world's new
terror hub. So they are kind of saying
that the Sahel region is where terrorism
happens now the global epicenter of
terrorism and they are not mentioned in
Pakistan in this in this regard. So
they're trying to whitewash Pakistan's
reputation and giving them this this
supposedly influential position in the
UN Security Council. It
um in in in the perspective of
terrorism. Well, once again, they're
trying to whitewash things. So it's kind
of a diplomatic victory for Pakistan.
It's not a diplomatic victory because it
doesn't really have the support of
hundreds of nations. It's it's it's like
a bone that has been thrown thrown
towards a dog. Here, chew on this bone.
This is your reward for your services
rendered. That's what this is. But it
can't be used to
prevent the potential continuation of
operations in they can't use that to
prevent
that. As says, I am a third year. First
of all, thank you, sir. Thank you. I am
a thirdyear
mega chemical from
Imperial. I'm a thirdyear Mang chemical.
What's mechanical engineer engineering
chemical from Imperial? I'm interested
in peptide crystallization and thinking
about doing a PhD but unsure if I should
do it in the US or not given the current
situation. I think it's risky now in the
US. You know what they're doing right
now currently is they are going after
Chinese students. Chinese students who
have these education visas F what F
whatever I think it's F visas is it or
whatever it is. Um, and they're revoking
the visas. So these students from China,
I'm sure most of them are not spies. I I
assume maybe I'm too naive, but maybe
I'm too naive still, but maybe not all
of them are spies, right? For the
Chinese Communist Party. So they have
spent a lot of money to come to the US
and they've taken admission. They've
done all the exams and they've cleared
everything. They have come legally after
spending so much money and the US is now
revoking their visas unilaterally.
There's nothing these kids can do about
it, right? So they're out. All these
years of hard work, all the money
invested, all of it down the drain. So
that's China. They're targeting China
right now. That's what the Trump
administration is doing. What's the
guarantee they will not look at India
next in the same
way? And right now they're increasing
their scrutin scrutiny all on all
student visa applications. Like they're
tripling the scrutiny. They want you to
um diverge all your social media
accounts and they will look at your
social media accounts and I'm sure even
if you have deleted stuff they can find
it because they own the social media
platforms. So they want to see if you
have said anything against their country
in the past or against any of their
allies or vasals that sort of thing. So
I think it's a difficult time to be an
Indian student who is thinking of going
to the US for further studies.
difficult, dangerous I'm I mean I
remember during the the COVID period
also when there were lockdowns and all
there were Indian students who had
secured admission after spending so much
money they reached the US after spending
so much money for the flight and they
told to go
back so anything can happen the only
safe place is your own country
um what are other potential locations uh
destinations maybe Australia is one but
I don't think Australia has such great
STEM unities I no offense to Australia,
but I'm not sure about that. Um, Germany
is a US vasal. They could follow suit
and they they've been rather
discriminatory towards Indian students
in the past.
Germany.
Um, yeah. So, I think it's kind of dodgy
right now. It's kind of dodgy. I can't
give you a final recommendation. You
will have to do your own risk analysis.
But hopefully what I told you gives you
some better context. It is kind of dodgy
right now. If I was 20 today and I
wanted to do do a PhD 22 or
whatever, I would be worried if I was
thinking of the
US. Susan says the nuke we the nukes we
talk of today are thermonuclear weapons.
Are there any countries that still
maintain an arsenal of traditional nukes
that is fish bombs? All nations maintain
an arsenal of fish and bombs.
Thermonuclear bombs are strategic
weapons. The tactical weapons are all
fish and
bombs mostly as as far as I understand.
I mean I would not use a thermonuclear
weapon as as as a tactical nuke as a
tactical nuke or a battlefield nuke.
Thermonuclear weapons are for a
different purpose. Very nasty purpose.
And then you have other weapons also.
But see the traditional low low yield
nukes fish bombs are still used.
Absolutely. No use in you still
stockpile them for tactical use. So um
it's not entirely correct that the nukes
we talk of today are only thermonuclear
weapons. It's not the case. Those are
strategic weapons. Those are to be
delivered in case of doomsday scenario
to ensure the complete annihilation of
your enemy because they have meadon plus
yields. Those are thermonuclear
weapons. Okay. MK. Thank you so much.
Thank you so much sir. Pravin says first
of all thank you. The question is who is
really winning the Russia Ukraine war?
Can we leverage this war to procure SU57
at discount? Who's winning right now?
It's a stalemate. Obviously Russia has
the upper hand. Ukraine is in no
position to see the question you to ask
yourself is very simple. Which side is
in a
position or has the capability to
destroy the other side completely to
inflict a permanent complete military
defeat on the opponent? Is
Ukraine in a position to inflict a
complete comprehensive military defeat
on Russia? Has it ever been in that
position? The answer is no and no. Is
Russia today capable of inflicting a
complete final military defeat on
Ukraine? It is. It would involve
tremendous amounts of force and
tremendous damage and destruction. But
they can do it. They can flatten
Ukraine. But Russia has chosen to take
it very slow. And because of that, now
in the past week, they've suffered
significant
losses. Uh and now Zalinski's star is
rising, his stature is rising, the West
is beginning to portray him like a
second V Winston Churchill. So that's
the deal. So maybe Russia will now take
some actions to, you know, rectify the
situation.
Maybe they will want to most likely to
end the war quickly now. We'll see. Can
we leverage this war to to procure the
Suko 57 at a discount? I think Russia
will be happy to give us the 57. I'm not
sure about the discounts and all but the
the thing is if we get the full transfer
of technology that's the most important
thing and of course if it comes at at a
discount why not but the most important
thing is full transfer of technology
including the source code including all
of it. That would be the most ideal
thing for us. Uh I think we should go
for that after properly scrutinizing the
offer and doing our due diligence. We
should go for it. Shibam says when will
India build scale power capacity for
AI? I think India the government of
India is now taking AI very seriously.
Uh and I'm sure there are
u projects underway to have our own
indigenous AI systems. not just a not
just a chatbot in a large language model
but something beyond that. So the real
utility of AI is not in the civilian
domain it's in the military domain in
the governance domain. So I think India
is in the process of doing this. Uh
Karnataka you're going to have some
um some developments there and so on. So
I think we're on the right track.
Vic post says did the oponyations give
birth to
quantum look I may be completely
ignorant but I don't see it that way I
may be completely wrong in this because
a lot of people believe this but I
haven't really read the opinions in
great detail
uh but quantum
mechanics see what you have is that
there are so many of these phenomena in
quantum mechanics that make no sense
quantum mechanics is not intuitive at
all. It has these extraordinarily
counterintuitive
um aspects to it and some of the
interpretations of quantum mechanics are
shocking, mind-boggling like multiple
universes, the quantum multiverse,
u quantum immortality and so on. These
are real possible interpretations of
quantum mechanism. These are similar to
what we have in the in in the Indian
philosophical text like the
opishations and so on. So the
interpretations are similar to what
Indians thought about thousands of years
ago. We thought about this without
solving the equations of or der or
deriving the equations of quantum
mechanics. So the oponyations did not
give birth to quantum mechanics. But
what the openish in etc talk spoke speak
about what Indian philosophical texts
speak about that is
now being seen as some of the
interpretations of quantum mechanics.
The quant interpretations are very
similar to what Indian philosophical
texts talk about. So there are
parallels which make us wonder what on
earth were our ancestors doing. How did
they thousands of years ago think of
these things which are now coming out of
quantum mechanics. That's the deal.
Alan Spice says, "How and why did
Singapore separate from Malaysia?" Now
that's an old story and I don't know
Leewan, you cried on in front of the
cameras for that. I think there were
differences on governance and I don't
remember exactly what the deal was right
now. There were differences on in
opinion about how the two nations should
proceed and uh Lee Kuanu wanted
something else and and Malaysia wanted
something else. That's as far as I can
remember right now. the specific
details. You're going to have to look it
up. Uh yeah, so I don't remember right
now exactly what it
was. Only Jam says why Hindu scripture
teaching in temples is not promoted at
least in BJP ruled states. It would
unite Hindus and promote use of Sanskrit
and unify Hindus. Well, unfortunately,
you see, I am
not one of the rulers of the BJP ruled
states. So, I don't know why it is.
you're going to have to ask the
governments in those states why it's not
being done. Uh Hindu scripture teaching
in
temples. It's a good idea. What's wrong
with it? Do it. But for that temples
would need state support, but we are a
secular nation. So we can't support the
temples with with public money. Of
course, we can support other things with
public money, which is perfectly fine in
secular Indian secularism. I think it's
it's ridiculous. India should
wholeheartedly, in my opinion, embrace
its cultural and civilizational identity
and values and traditions
officially, but that's not the case. So
that's where we are today and it's
sad. MK, was the US pro or anti-rexit
and why? Well, the US never said
anything about this. They said it's a
internal matter of the EU or something,
but I assure you they were pro Brexit. I
assure you they wanted more direct
control over the UK which would not be
possible if the UK remained part of the
EU then they can only control the UK
indirectly through Brussels. So I think
it was a great deal for the US that the
U the Brexit
happened. Okay. Mr. 88 says says that if
Trump was silent shouldn't that make it
more obvious that he was aware? I mean
he was very quick with the balam thing
happened or
we or we started operation tindur look
Mr. Trump makes it a point to tweet
about everything and anything. No matter
what's happening, he's tweeting. He like
tweets dozens of times a day. Twitter or
or or he post puts posts these days on.
So on what truth social and he has an
opinion over everything and if something
happens, he'll weigh in about
it.
But I'm assuming you're talking about uh
I'm assuming you're talking about
spiderweb. Maybe you are. But when this
operation spider web happened, nothing
not a statement from from Trump for 48
hours because there was nothing for him
to take credit for, right? I don't think
he was
aware. I don't think he was aware at
all. I think he was shocked. He was
shocked into silence. And his first
mention of operation spiderweb was when
he put out a post on truth social about
his conversation with Mr. Putin which
involved a discussion about the planes
that were hit.
So I think he's been completely shocked
and he's been flabbergasted. What on
earth happened? They're not playing
paying me due respect, due difference.
How dare they keep me out of it? He was
very upset and very annoyed. I get the
feeling he was he had absolutely no idea
about
this. Si SSS says DRDO is working on
human robots that will join our military
by 2027. How can they help us in
warfare? By taking bullets and nothing
happens to them. If you if a human takes
a bullet, you are incapacitated at best.
I mean, you can fight, but you know,
you're going to need attention very
rapidly, but robots, I think they can
take a lot of damage damage and they can
go deep into enemy territory, and we
don't have to worry about a robot being
captured, for example, or killed, but we
don't want our our people to be
captured. So, that's just one example of
uh how they can help us in warfare. And
robots, if they're AI equipped, they
will always aim properly. They won't
miss the target. You see, they won't
miss the
target. So many advantages of having
robots. You just send 10,000 robots to
into battle. They'll take P for you.
They'll neutralize all the Pakistani
terrorists and all the
Pakistani
regulars and then we can walk in. I
mean, imagine that scenario. Isn't it
great if we have robots in battle? There
you have it, sir. Sedartha Sharma says,
"I want to learn about Indian dynasties
before the frequent invasions. What
sources would you suggest? Also would
love to watch a series about from me
about this." Yeah. Well, there's only a
certain number of certain number of
things I can do on an ongoing basis. The
the geo strategy podcast that I'm doing
is it it takes a tremendous amount of
research. I have to go through more than
a thousand pieces of high signal
intelligence per week. Yeah. I'm also
trying to continue the uh understanding
America podcast which involves a lot of
reading. If I'm doing all that, how on
earth will I be able to uh you know do a
series about Indian history? I would
love to. I would love to. I'm not saying
it's a bad suggestion. It's a great
suggestion and thank you for that. But
at this point in time it's not possible.
Maybe in the future I would love to. Uh
where can you read about Indian
dynasties before the frequent invasions?
I think you know uh you can read up RC
Majunar. That's a great one. There's a
book about South Indian history and I
don't remember who the author was,
Nilakantan or something. Maybe I'll put
it out uh separately but I think RC
Mundar is is a great source. Uh of
course some of his information will most
likely be outdated because he wrote the
books almost 100 years ago but it's
still a great source and a very detailed
source. So maybe you can start with RC
Majunar. He's got this this long series
about Indian history. I think more than
10 books if I'm not mistaken. So, that's
a good source to go to. Thank you.
Anonymous says, "Why can't lab diamonds
be used in jet engine turbines?"
Well, it's a good question. Well, okay.
Let's do some research, shall we? Let's
do a bit of
research. Um, what's the uh combustion
temperature of diamonds?
Right. First of all, jet engine
temperature.
Jet jet engine
uh a average temperature
um how many,000° how hot? Okay, so this
is an AI overview 1500° let's say now
1500° keep it in mind. Now com
combustion temperature
diamond
diamond see 900°.
So if you have a diamond turbine blade
in a jet engine which re reaches 1500°
the diamond will end up as ash because
it is carbon at the end of the day. So
that's why you can't and also it has
other characteristics that you that you
don't want in a jet engine turbine
geopolitical dub. Thank you very much
sir. Thank you. Sahil Rajesh Lande says
your thoughts on China's agot terrorism
in the US. Well, plausible
deniability sending sending some kind of
a fungus, a blight of some kind through
students or or researchers or whatever.
They will try everything at their
disposal. They will I'm sure the US will
also reciprocate or must be doing things
similar to that.
So, Sergeant Skylan says, "How would you
rank the IIAF?" Now the Indian air force
today the most powerful air force is the
US air force then the US marine air
force and then then the US navy air
force that's three the second most power
after that you would have I would
imagine the Russian air force then the
Chinese air force then the Indian air
force so 1 2 3 4 5 six number six or
something but when when it comes to
national strength the US is number one
Russia is number two China is number
three India is number four that's where
I would rank India
uh Mike says I like Japanese history and
culture. The Maji Empire modernized
Japan and made it a great power. Why did
the Maratas fail to create something of
the Maji Empire and become a contend
contender in the Second World War? The
Maji Empire nearly destroyed Japanese
culture. By the way, they modernized
Japan at the cost of Japan's traditional
culture and they turned Japan into
something it never was, an adheric
culture, a Dharmic Empire. And that's
why Japan committed, Japanese soldiers
committed all those horrific atrocities
they did in Nanjing and Manuria and
whatnot. The Maji Empire tried to uproot
Japan's 2,000 plus year old culture.
They tried to wipe Buddhism out. They
destroyed the samurai system, the
shogunit, everything. And yeah, it made
Japan a great power for a while. But
then you know what happened
eventually? The Maratas never had the
intention of removing Dharma from India.
Um and uh where did Marata's failed to
create something like the major empire?
Look, the Marata
Empire was destroyed by the British
after the second Anglo Marata war. But
the reason for the decline of the Marata
Empire was infighting. It's always
succession that goes along that causes
infighting and then you have this tussle
political tussle for supremacy and you
forget what the big picture is that you
know you need to run the empire and
safeguard the country and that's what
happened. That's what where it went
wrong. My friends, Akshai VHMA says,
"How do you rate the US current foreign
and immigration policy? Will it help
them in the long run for creating
jobs?" Foreign policy is right now half
a hazard. They're imposing tariffs
everywhere, even on their own allies.
Their own allies are now in the position
of at the point of, you know,
reciprocating with further tariffs on
the US. And the the Trump administration
seems to think that they can get away by
by arm twisting everybody because they
are more powerful. But it's going to
cause longlasting long longlasting
illwill towards the US and it's not good
overall. It's not a good foreign policy
to have immigration policy. They are
they're cracking down on lots of things.
They are deporting lots of what they
call illegal aliens and so on. I mean I
if somebody is in the country legally
they should be deported. Nothing wrong
with that. I completely support that. No
question about it. Um, so if they're
able to deport all the illegal aliens,
it will kind of to a certain small
extent ease the pressure on their
society and economy and it it will free
up more jobs for actual citizens. So
that would be good. Uh, immigration
policy. What else? Uh, they want
high-skilled immigrants, very valuable
immigrants, not not low-skilled
immigrants. So I think that's a work in
progress. So um the current foreign
policy is is kind of chaotic and I think
it's a little counterproductive for the
US interests. The immigration policy
seems to be a somewhat better and maybe
if it is implemented and enforced
properly it may be good for the US and
it may free up more jobs for American
citizens. Maybe even create jobs
possibly. Maybe the foreign policy is
all about creating jobs, imposing
tariffs on things that are coming from
outside so that the American economy
will have to create those, you know,
products at home, but that will come at
a much higher cost. So it'll have
problems, inflationary problems and so
on. But let's see. So overall, the
foreign policy isn't
great. Immigration policy makes more
sense. Nilles Patil says, "What's the
battle of anti-atam change in the US
psyche?" I haven't reached there yet.
I haven't reached that yet. So I'm not
sure. Uh but yeah. Yeah. It's a it's a
pivotal it's a pivotal
uh ep uh what you could say chapter in
US
history. Abishek shastav says your views
on pronabistri chat sutra AI app. I am
not aware of it. Pranov mystery is is a
pretty solid technical guy. Uh I
remember watching videos of him like 15
years ago in which he was the first guy
to you know have these the internet
internet of things kind of thing and he
was very innovative and so on but I
haven't positionally seen this uh chat
sutra AI app should I see it now I think
no not right now I'll look at look into
it later so I I don't have views right
now because I haven't seen that
yet. Mr. Aiator says if the exchange of
a 100 nukes between two nations can can
end human life on earth then why does
the number of nukes matter? We or North
Korea should be as much feared as
Russia. Why does Russia's number of
nukes matter more? Yeah. Be you are
right beyond a certain beyond a certain
scale number of nukes doesn't matter.
And that's why you know during the cold
war the first cold war in the 70s and
80s the two nations the US and the USSR
had these series of treaties that cut
down the number of nuclear weapons
because it made no sense for each nation
to have 10,000 plus nuclear warheads.
Made no sense whatsoever. Too much
maintenance, too much headache. Cut it
down. Cut it down. Cut it down. They
also had this thing that they would
not mate their nuclear weapons with
strategic bombers and the strategic
bombers would would remain on display
and they would not be attached the
missiles or or nuclear weapons will not
be attached to the aircraft. There was
the start start one start to whatever
treaty and so on. So it doesn't make
sense to have so many nuclear weapons.
But still I think both nations US and
Russia today have around 5,000 roughly
give or take nuclear weapons.
Um now the question is how many nukes if
they're detonated can end human life on
earth? If a 100 nukes are detonated will
it end human life? It will cause come
some kind of atmospheric disturbance. It
will cause some kind of mild nuclear
winter
scenario. Uh but it won't end life on
earth. 100 nuclear weapons. It will
cause problems climate problems and so
on. It won't end human life. It may
affect human life maybe maybe a few
million people may die possibly which is
already a disaster but it won't end
human life and nations like the US etc
can can potentially deal with this such
such scenarios but if you have a
thousand weapons that is catastrophic
and that's like world ending scenario so
that's why nations with 100 200 weapons
are not that feared and obviously
um nations like ours
will probably not want to use them. Uh
Rahul Lakman says, "Are there plans for
space tourism by India private or public
sector?" Not that I know of. Anything at
all? Nothing that I know of. Uh for
space tourism, you need significant
space assets infrastructure. You needed
a you need at least one space station.
You need the ability to send people up
on demand. We don't have that right now.
ISRO has a very shoring budget and
shoestring capabilities despite being a
fantastic organization with fantastic
people. And we have achieved so much in
this road despite such low budgets. So
uh space tourism is a luxury and we are
I don't think anybody in India has any
plans for space tourism whether it's the
public sector or private sector at this
point in
time. The power says why is
Elon posting against Trump now?
Divorced. Divorced. Yes sir.
Divorced. It's
done. Yeah. Nikl Bansali says, "What
would you define as Indian values are
the values that come out of the Vedas of
the Uponyas? the traditional cultural
civilizational values of India which
come out of the various philosophical
schools of thought whether it is yoga
mimmansa
u what whatever else we have whether it
is the u jana philosophy whether it is
the the sananka philosophy both the
philosophy even the charvaka philosophy
or the vidanta philosophy all these
philosophical schools of thought they
have a shared set of set of values no
matter how different the schools of
thought are they have these shared
values that nonviolence is superior and
preferable to violence being vegetarian
is preferable and superior to being
non-vegetarian and you have to uh serve
dharma uh a hinsa is bad which means we
have to destroy a hinsa and so on so
forth all the values that are common in
all the phil philosophical schools of
thought are the Indian
values chawan thank you sir thank you
very much recently we saw how far India
has progressed in AI in warfare. How can
we Indian citizens best use AI
kosh to advance AI innovation research
innovation using government provided
data sets models and tools? Have you
explored it? I have not explored it.
What is AI kosh? Let me try and find out
very rapidly quickly. Let me Google it.
What is AI kosh?
Um EI kosh let's see what is EI kosh AI
kosh AI kosh a platform that provides
repository of data sets oops data sets
models and use cases to enable AI
innovation it features AI sandbox
capabilities through an integrated
something and this looks like a
government thing that's fascinating I
was not aware of this So I'm not that
much of an adopter of AI. So maybe
that's why I was not aware of it. But
it's interesting to see this. Uh so
yeah, India has progressed significantly
in AI warfare. No question. How can
Indian citizens best use AI coach to
advance research AI research and
innovation using government provided
data sets? I'll have to dig deep into
that and look into what kind of data
sets are being provided to us. um what
AI tools are are part of this AI
coach? What models do we
have? Can we download the models and and
use them at home
uh on our own systems or do we have to
be connected like with charge GPT or or
whatever else you have? I have not
explored it. I came to know about it
just now because of you. So I thank you
for it. I've not explored it but I I
I'll make sure I do before the next live
stream because this is interesting. This
is very interesting. Do we already have
AI systems and AI AI models of our own?
Interesting. So I I'll check it out but
as of now I can't answer the question
because I haven't used it. So anyway,
thank you so much. Susant Das says is
the recent movement in Nepal to bring
back the monarchy India's reply to the
US or the regime change in Bangladesh?
Um I hope so if it is the case and I
hope that the monarchy comes back in
Nepal because that's been Nepal's
traditional system for centuries since
the 18th century they've had a monarchy
in Nepal the first king was
Rana I forget the name forget the name
but yeah the kingdom of Nar in Nar
Valley and and yeah it would be so nice
for the people to of Nepal to have their
monarchy back I'll be so happy for them
Um I'm not sure if it's India's reply to
the US. In case it is, well, good job
India. But yeah, it should happen.
Just just a movement happening without
without success is no point, right? It
should happen. They should get their
monarchy back. They should have their
king king
back. Rohan says, do you agree with
George Freriedman's view who's a
renowned geopolitical expert? He says
that Japan will research is a great
power and the rise of Poland is a big
power. Poland is being positioned by by
NATO and the US as the next big bulvar
against a hypothetical Russian westward
expansion and Poland is being
transformed into a military power.
Significant military power. So yes,
Poland is rising as a big power. Their
economy is doing well, etc. Anyway, good
for the good for the people of Poland.
Good. But they should not allow
themselves to be used as a pawn on
someone's geopolitical chessboard.
That's the only concern. But Poland is
rising. Sure.
Will Japan research as a great power? I
would love nothing more than that to
happen. Japan is a wonderful nation,
great culture, great civilization,
wonderful
people. I would love for Japan to rise
again as a great power and as a as a as
a Japanese cultural entity, not as a as
an Abrahamized entity or a or a
dassinated entity like it was under the
major restoration. But will it happen? I
think unfortunately it's unlikely for
this to happen right now. the birth
rates and all. It's a disaster in Japan
and now they're bringing in immigrants
into Japan. That's a disaster. That's a
disaster. Very sad. Diva Sharma says,
"Jeo strategy with AC is amazing. Keep
it up." Thank you very much, ma'am.
Thank you. I'm assuming you're a ma'am.
Thank you. Um Vishal Chri says, "Subra
Swami stand on current government seems
suspicious. Revealing number details of
numbers of fighters short calling
India's GDP figures fake. any opinion I
don't examine Indian politics
um I look into geopolitics I am not
aware of what who is saying and who is
not saying and all that and so many
people do that right there are so many
experts who go dig deep into Indian
politics and they can give you the right
answers about this I have not seen Mr.
Mr. Swami's statements. I'm not aware of
what he has been saying. As far as I
know, he's no longer part of the Lok
Sabha, Raja Sabha, whatever it was. So I
can't say I don't know about that. Not
aware of it.
Sorry. Jiny says, "Good morning. If
hypothetically, so you are in Canada, I
suppose." Okay. Good morning. If
hypothetically India gets $30 trillion
somehow, how will you allocate the funds
for the growth of India? I would
allocate at least 5% of uh the GDP uh
annual GDP uh to the defense of the
country defense budget then I would
allocate a significant proportion to R&D
and then I would revamp the Indian
education system with all these funds 30
trillion is a great amount of money
invest like at least a trillion into
revamping the education system which is
easier said than done I mean you can
invest the money it's easy if you have
it but revamping it the whole system the
rotten system with so many
entrenched you know stakeholders that'll
be difficult it'll cause chaos so be it
whatever it is so yeah I would focus on
the longstanding issues which have which
have long-standing benefits long-lasting
benefits deep benefits in the long
term so that's what I would do the rest
obviously has to be spended governance
and and yeah if you get $30 trillion you
could purchase a lot of hardware maybe
you can transfer the Rafal
Rafal U production line to India and the
Suka 57 production line to India and
have all the technology transferred to
India, jet engines and whatnot. So you
can do a lot with $30 trillion. But
where would I start? I would start with
allocating 5% for defense per
year. Um and maybe of these so so I'm
not really answering your question
there. I'm talking about $30 trillion
GDP per cap GDP annually. No, but using
a lump sum $30
trillion. Yeah. So I would I would
uh I would use at least 5 trillion
trillion of those for the Indian defense
whatever whatever the gaps are whatever
the shortcomings comingings are and the
rest I would have to think about it
because I haven't thought about what I
would do with $30 trillion. But I'm sure
there's a lot of good you can do, a lot
of holes that can be plugged. Um, a lot
of infrastructure that can be built, a
lot of weapons that can be bought, lot
of uh high quality universities and
institutes that that can be created. You
can invest maybe at least a few trillion
trillion of those into
ISRO. Yeah. And and uh and so on to
create a proper space program and so on.
really now says who has fusion nukes do
we are they more advanced we have fusion
nukes these are called thermonuclear
weapons it's a three-stage process
chemic conventional explosive gives rise
to a fusion reaction fusion reaction
which in turn gives rise to a fusion
reaction it's called a hydrogen bomb or
a thermonuclear bomb u two-stage
three-stage devices the first stage is
conventional chemical explosives we have
it the Chinese have it the Americans
have it the Russians have it do the
North Koreans have it possibly
Okay. Does Israel have it? I have no
idea. But they have nukes. Does Pakistan
have thermonuclear bombs? If the
Americans have given them, sure. Or
maybe the Chinese gave them. Sure. So
yeah, they are more advanced. It takes a
little bit more of engineering to make
it happen. The fusion process. Uh so
they are more advanced and they are more
powerful significantly more powerful
because a fusion reaction the fusion of
hydrogen atoms into helium helium atoms
the output is helium atoms and a
tremendous amount of energy way more
energy than is that is given out by a
fish reaction so that's why they are
more powerful kis thank you very much
welcome to the channel zea za thank you
very much welcome to the channel I never
ever tell anybody to buy the membership
but some of you still buy it so thank
you so much I'm very grateful for that.
You're really supporting the channel. I
really appreciate that. Thank you. As
says, "I'm a British Indian citizen.
First of all, thank you. Should I back
off with a PhD in the US given I never
had any social media profile?" I think
if you're a British Indian citizen
citizen, if you have a British passport,
go for it. Absolutely go for the US. No
issues. It won't matter what the color
of his skin is as long as you have a
British passport and you never had any
social media profile. Well, what else do
you want? The course is clear, my
friend. Go for it. Go for it. As long as
you have a British passport, there's no
problem. They only are they are only
targeting people from who come who have
Asian passports, mainly China right now,
but potentially also India. So, you're
good to go. Uh the UV Mishas, the UV
Mishra says, what would be India take on
Pakistan's new UN position? I think it
is deplorable. I think it is regrettable
as the global Indian ambassador to the
world. I declare that this is a
regrettable thing to do and the United
Nations should be ashamed of itself for
elevating Pakistan to such a position
where it is in charge of
counterterrorism in in some way. It's
deplorable. It's regrettable. It is
shameful for an organization for the UN
to give the world's epicenter of
terrorism this position. That's it.
Krauss Nerf says, "I asked GPT, okay,
how people outside of India can help the
Dharmic cause. It responded well. Short
URL at R. Okay, that's the that's the
URL. People should see it." Well, uh,
should I see it? Maybe I should. Maybe
I'll take a look at what that is. Let us
find out. So, let me put this thing on
the screen.
Um, here we have it. And let me try and
check out the
URL. Short
URL at
slash R
DLX. What's it
say? Page not found. Short URL dot at
short URL. R D LX. Okay, maybe some I
I'll do that in my my free time. Looks
like I was not a maybe I got the the URL
wrong or something, but okay, let let
people check it out for sure and thank
you for sharing this. I appreciate it.
Jugen says China controls 90 actually
95% of the rare earth elements. The US
is begging. I'm not sure the US is
begging in front of China. Is China the
next superpower? No, it's not. Thus far,
it's not. AI US lack behind
China. The US is is at the forefront of
AI, but China is showing signs of
potentially catching up in the future.
It's not very far behind the US. Yeah.
And will US ever protect China at the
cost of its business with China? Will
the US ever protect
Taiwan at the cost of its business with
China? The US is decoupling from China
in case people haven't noticed. The US
has imposed 145% tariffs on China and
then they brought it back to a certain
thing a small period of time for for u
for for to to to have breathing space
for talks. But the US is going all out
against China. They want to destroy
their economic relationship with China.
They want everything all their American
companies to pull out of China. That's
why India has the
opportunity. The US is not valuing its
business with China. It wants to end
everything. It's nuking it. When it
comes to Taiwan, the the US will protect
Taiwan or if China is militarily strong
and it'll take Taiwan, it'll the US will
ensure that Taiwan is entirely destroyed
before China gets hold of
it and the US is not begging in front of
China. The US has alternatives even
though the Chinese control 90% of the
rare earth elements 95% actually and
they have imposed stringent restrictions
which means the US gets nothing. Now
there are alternatives. Australia is a
big source and Australia if Australia
ramps up its production it could become
a viable significantly viable uh
alternative to China. India is engaging
with Australia on this front and so on.
Is China the next superpower? I hope not
and probably it's not in in a position
to be the next superpower anytime soon
anytime soon at all or ever
possibly. Dave Chandan Malik says India
got burned by the US in 1971. Oh yes,
backing Pakistan. Oh yes, but we gave
them the best response possible by
viscting Pakistan and we also got burned
by the post98 nuc sanctions. Yes, we
did. Can we trust the US now with the
quad I set with with China? How do we
use it? Stay autonomous and avoid
betrayal of the US flips. The
US we have to understand one thing very
clearly. The US doesn't wish India to
grow. It doesn't want to see India as as
as a 10 $15 economy by the 2040 horizon.
It doesn't want a new China to emerge in
15 years. India could can very much
emerge as as as the next China in 15
years if we just keep up with the
current growth trajectory. So they will
do everything they can to curtail our
growth, to hamper our growth and cause
all kinds of
problems. Can we trust the US? We can
trust the US to do all of this.
the quad all that is nice to
counterbalance China. We have some
utility in that in that matter but apart
from that the US wants India to stay
where it is. They want our growth to
stagnate. They will do their best to
ensure this this happens. So we can
trust them to have that sort of approach
towards us. So how do we stay autonomous
etc. We have to have a policy of
multi-alignment. Work with everybody.
Cultivate all possible uh friends that
we can geopolitically whatever
friendship is possible. Yes. And we
should also have excellent relations
with other powers. What other powers
exist apart from the US and China?
Russia for example. We should maintain
our excellent relations with Russia. We
should also cultivate our excellent ties
with France and the global south
nations. And if we balance all these
things together, we can stay autonomous
and that's what one uh would like to do.
Nachiket Jay Raman says did USDNI
predicted major IndiaPakistan conflict
before 2026? How how is that? What is
DNI? USDNI. USDNI director of national
intelligence. Is it Oh, who is the DNI?
Is it
Tulsi? Okay. Whoever it is USDNI Tulsi
is it
Tulsi? It is Tulsi Gabard. So did she
predict a major India Pakistan conflict
before 2026? I'm not
sure. And maybe they have their
calculations of you know predictions,
predictive
analytics. I'm sure I suppose they use
all kinds of supercomputing power and AI
and all that. So maybe you can war game
scenarios like humans can't. Maybe that
can allow them to predict stuff
possibly.
Shuban Dubai says, "What's your take on
India acquiring 31 MQ9B drones from the
US considering their advanced
surveillance and possible nuclear
integration? Can this be moved be
trusted strategically?" Look, we have if
we these are I think surveillance
drones. If we try to modify them for
nuclear uh delivery, they will not allow
it to happen and they will disable the
drones remotely. Guaranteed. Guaranteed.
And uh you look when if you acquire
weapon systems from the Americans they
always come with some kind of problem
with some kind of comp compromised
situation the Australians know it very
well. FA18 fighter planes they bought
from the Americans completely useless
for two decades. So yeah if we use it in
a way that the Americans don't like it
they're going to disable it
immediately. And that's how it is. The
reason they've given they've sold this
to us is because we can use this to do
surveillance in the Indian Ocean region
in the Bay of Bengal region, Chinese uh
you know inroads into the region and so
on. That's why so yeah it's it's it's
dangerous to purchase American weapon
systems because you know they are not
reliable. The Americans can switch them
off. Zea Zea Well thank you very much
sir. Thank you very much in video. Do
Muslims in the subcontinent have Turk
DNA? Very little. Very negligible. Most
of them have absolutely no Turk DNA.
Maybe 1% or 2% of them may have maybe 5
10% Turk DNA. Most of them have
absolutely no Turk DNA. They're us.
They're our people. Um the in the actual
article didn't talk about Muslims in
Afghanistan, Pakistan. Rather talked
about six random Muslim communities.
Nature genetic article from 2012 says 65
65% pashons are distant from Indian
people. Okay. But I I have seen genetic
studies about pashons. I I obviously
don't have the access to it right now
because I have to dig through all my uh
all that. But the pashons are
essentially an extension of the north
Indian population.
And in the past 1,000 years, many other
ethnic groups have settled in
Afghanistan, right? Which means that
there's going to be dilution of the
original ethnicity. No question about
it. But overall, among the various
ethnic groups in Afghanistan, the
Pashons are the largest ethnic group and
they are the indigenous eth ethnic group
and they still have some remnants of
their pre invasion culture. some of I
mean the atundance for example I mean if
you see the atund dance you'll be
astonished what what on earth and so on
uh there there will be some genetic
dilution some influx some introgression
of foreign genetics
uh but overall the pashons are our
people and you you can look at other
research papers also I suppose because I
remember doing that a long time ago and
I it said that the pashon population is
an extension of the northern Indian
population and they have had genetic
influx from other surrounding regions
also because of the geographical
location of Gandhar or
Afghanistan. Sergeant Skylin says do you
think the do you think India used the
S400 better than Russia? We we don't
know. I don't know because we don't have
the data. I don't have access to the
data of how much h how to what extent
was the S400 used in the 3-day war
against Pakistan. As far as I know, we
used it once as far as I know. to my
very limited understanding because we
had that interception of Pakistani
missile ballistic missile possibly or
sah harana that was most likely in my
opinion the S400 I I still may be wrong
about that so can't really compare a
limited use versus what Russia has been
using in the Ukraine conflict can't
really compare the two warrior says root
cause of anti-semitism in detail Nazism
etc the Europeans have persecuted Jews
for almost 2,000 years. The root cause
is that they claim all kinds of things
about Jews, that Jews are outsiders and
Jews have some practices that the
Europeans don't like and some kind of
stories of blood liel or something. I'm
not sure what it is. We don't understand
these things. The Jews have lived in
India for 2,000 years, never ever been
persecuted in India. So, we don't
understand what anti-mitism is. The
Europeans, they have given rise to it, I
suppose. Okay. Hm. Big fan. Well, thank
you very much, sir. I really appreciate
it. Thank you,
sir. Ankita G. Thank you very much,
ma'am. Thank
you. Okay. ABM Studio says, "Russia is
offering Sukoy 57s with full technology
transfer. They want to produce Sukoy 57s
not just for India but for the world.
Outstanding. What could be a possible
reason why our government is not taking
it up?" Uh, we have not rejected it.
That offer has just come to the table
pretty recently. Now when such an offer
is made, you have to sit down and look
at all the details. What is part of the
offer? What are all the technical
details? You have to do your detailed
due diligence. Takes time. Then you may
find that some things are the way are a
different way from what you want. Then
you can do a counter offer and so on so
forth. So I think the government of
India should should move on this as
quickly as possible. And I yesterday I
think or day before when was it? I think
yesterday I made the prediction that
there's a 80% chance that by the end of
this year we will go ahead with this
offer. Maybe a modified version of the
offer but this
offer. So our government has not refused
it. I think we are studying it
carefully. Studying the offer carefully.
You to look at all the technical
specifications and considerations of the
offer. So I think I I predict there's an
80% chance that by the end of the year
India will go ahead with this and that
will be fantastic as long as the offer
is great.
Rashankumar says as it feels like we are
alone and the world is against us. Look
friends the world is how many people
some 7 billion something we are 1.4
billion of us how can 1.4 4 billion
people be alone. We have each other. Why
do we need anybody else? And the whole
world is not against us. It's only some
countries that are against us. Most of
the world actually likes us. All the
global south countries, they are they
are on our side at least. I know it's
silent. They're silently supporting us,
but they're on our
side. Okay. Grock says, "What's
happening to the Chinese economy?" So,
VGI crisis explanation.
um you get this this report of the
Chinese economy collapsing or there's
some crisis or the other all the time. I
don't think it's an economy in a crisis.
I'm sure there are issues. Uh they said
the housing bubble is going to break and
they've been saying that for a very long
time. I don't think that's the case. I
think the Chinese economy is doing
reasonably well. There are issues, no
question about it, but I don't see it,
you know, I don't see it uh going down.
I don't see there being a crisis anytime
soon. Um it'll It'll be okay I guess for
the Chinese
economy. As says, "After my education,
what can I do to help India? I'm
thinking of setting up a pharmaceutical
company in India, but I don't know how
to pursue it. After your education, what
you need to do is to earn a tremendous
amount of wealth outside of
India. Once you get your degree, it's
not that's not the time to come and help
India. Once you get your
degree, set up an industry, set up um a
company, set up
whatever whatever it is in the west and
make it succeed. Become super wealthy.
Once you have a few hundred million
dollars to throw around, that's when you
come to India. Then you can set up a
pharmaceutical company or whatever you
want in India. By that time, you will
have experience. You will know how the
world works. You will know how to deploy
financial assets and other assets.
So learn all the tricks of the trade,
all the skills outside of India. Gain
all the experience outside of India
while staying in touch with India so
that you know how things are in India as
well. And then once you are sufficiently
wealthy, that's when you set up your
company in India. Because if you have
$10,000 to invest in India, what's
what's what's going to be the effect of
that? But let's say you've got a hundred
million to invest in India. Well, now
you're going to have a genuine positive
effect on India. So that's what I would
say. Wait until you're in your 30s or
40s and do your best to become super
wealthy. I wish you all the best,
sir. Okay. Akar says, "Why doesn't Bat
with
consensus peacefully unify Nepal,
Bhutan, Srianka itself? After all, we
have the same culture. We don't follow
our
culture. Nepal is still still very much
a Hindu nation. If we integrate Nepal
into India, Nepal will have to follow
secularism. Do you want that on on the
on our dear Nepalese
people? Let Nepal be separate but still
one with
us. If you integrate Sri Lanka into
India, Sri Lanka will go from a Buddhist
country to a secular country. Imagine
what will it will do to Sri Lanka's
culture. Do you want that? Do you want
all the problems of India to go to all
the other countries? Bhutan is a
Buddhist country. You wanted to become a
secular
country. It's not a good idea. You see,
sir, please, please
think differently. Think critically.
India secularism is a disaster. We don't
want to impose that on our people in
Nepal, in Bhutan and Sri Lanka and
wherever else. Let them currently be be
different be be a separate be separate
entities. In the future when we
reconnect with our civilizational
heritage, cultural heritage and we
embrace it officially then we can think
about these things then they will also
be happy to come back to us. Right now
it's not a good
idea. Okay. I see BM says a turbo
question IRA Irish Republican Army is it
possible the global glo global drug
trade and cartels exists as a way to
keep Mexico etc in check independent of
the US?
M so IRA in Mexico is not a big a
connection there but IRA there I'm sure
there was some drug funding in there I
remember reading a book called Mr.
Nice. Yeah. Ireland one of was one of
the transit main transit hubs if I
recall. So why does the drug trade
happen? Why are all these cartels why
why do they exist? They serve some
purpose otherwise they would have been
wiped out a long time ago.
And yeah, it's it's it's a way to keep
Mexico, Mexico in check, in Colombia in
check and keep them off balance, keep
them always on in all kinds of trouble.
You could say that, you know, there are
all these dirty tactics that are used to
keep countries down. So I would say
there is a pro nonzero probability that
this may be true. Let's put it that way.
Yes. Shivarput says,
Shahar gorakur panam gurudev pranam g
pranam thank you so much I'm sorry I I
read Hindi very slowly because I spend
much of my formative time outside of
India and yeah so I can read Hindi but
I'm slow so when are you going to see a
podcast with Sanjadishar well ask
Sanjadik Shitsar to to invite me I will
go and I'll do a podcast with him I'll
be happy to do
that anyhow Gorakpur you're in Gorakpur
wonderful place I've never been there I
would love to visit but anyway Namaskar
to you and thank you so
much. Weberinda says is our diversity
killing us rather than benefiting us.
What diversity do we have? We have the
same culture, same civilization, all of
us. We have different languages and all
does and yeah we have so many different
ideas and different ways of living our
lives and all different lifestyles and
all is that killing us or benefiting us?
Maybe maybe it's it's a challenge when
you are up against the Abrahamic forces
which are like mono mono monochromatic
monotheistic mono everything complete
you know just one one shade of gray and
we are so different so that's why we
can't unite possibly so yeah it it is
certainly one of our weaknesses sadly
what should have been a
strength preltp says if India collapsed
in future what signs would we see god
forward forbid how city of London
sovereignty. What Switzerland has WF
like horrible or organization like three
questions? If India collapsed in the
future, what signs would we see? You
would see some what there are different
kinds of collapse. Economic
collapse, economic collapse, there's
military collapse, there's foreign
takeover, there are so many different
things that can happen for a nation to
collapse. And each of them has a
different set of signals and signs and
symptoms that you could possibly see
coming.
So one thing that could potentially
happen to a nation hypothetically is a
regime
change that's a cool like thing or
something you can see that coming if
there's an economic collapse happening
in a nation you can see that coming from
far away you know the economy is going
down the inflation is rising jobs not
there and so on so forth all of that and
so on so similarly you know there are
set of signs and symptoms for each
different kind or type of collapse and
god forbid it should never happen to
India how did the city of Len London get
sovereignty. The city of London is not a
sovereign nation. It's the capital of
the UK. I'm not sure it's if it's
sovereign nation. I don't think it is.
I'm pretty sure it's
not. Uh why Switzerland has WF like
horrible organization, World Economic
Forum? Switzerland is is the is the kind
of the European capital of all these
things. They have um a very nice,
beautiful nation, very nice, very
friendly, very boring people, but very
nice people. Nothing abnormal, out of
the normal happens there. And you have
these global institutions that have you
know centers over there like the like
the United Nations and the World
Economic Forum and so on so forth. It is
just what it
is. Potato praiser says watching you
since 10th completed 12th. Well, thank
you so much. Appreciate that. And
congratulations on completing the 12th.
Thinking of taking BBA in marketing,
concerned of AI, any better options or
is BBA okay? Your thoughts? Commerce.
Bachelor of business administration. I
suppose what that's what BBA is. Well,
if it's something that you like and if
that's the kind of aptitude you have to
do something in business and commerce
and all, good, go for
it. Um, any better options? Look, I am
What's the better options? the best
um I I don't know much about what are
the better option in the in the Indian
education system. I think that whatever
it depends on what your overall
objective is. Do you want to be a
business person? Do you want to start a
business? Do you want to inherit
somebody's business? Is that what you're
in line for? Do you want to be an
entrepreneur and take some risks or do
you just want to have a job and work for
somebody? Depending on the answers to
all this, I can tell you perhaps what
the right thing is. Without knowing it,
it's very hard for me to say. But if you
think that BBA in marketing is great
then you must have thought about it and
you must be yeah then maybe it's the
right right thing for you. So commerce
right BBA bachelor of business
administration and then you can have an
MBA well that's great then you can have
a very lucrative job in a company. So
sounds like a sounds like a good plan
sir. Anyhow thank you so much and thank
you so much for watching me for all
these years and I can only wish you the
very best going forward sir. Thank you
so much. Akar says, "Thank you, sir. If
BA doesn't trust the USA with fighter
jets as it division is over sovereignty,
then why are we acquiring GE 404 engines
that can be disabled remotely? Is there
no alternative in any other country?
Somehow we have acquired we are buying
those. I think for some reason we have
decided or or people have decided that
this this is the best possible engine
for the Thus. They just is a single
fighter single engine fighter plane and
maybe the GE4 FC F404 engine
specifications match what we require.
Maybe we must have maybe maybe we have
tried with other countries to acquire
some other engines and maybe they did
not give us the best possible deal.
Maybe they were armed possibly by the
Americans into not giving it. Maybe the
Russian certain engines are too big, too
bulky for the ages. I'm not sure what it
is. There could be so many different
factors that have compelled us to
acquire the GEF404 engine which is now
being
delayed. So that's a form of leverage
over us by the Americans. Okay, I'm
going to take like two three more
questions and then I'm going to be done
with these. So yeah, you can yeah I'm
ending soon. Kumar Kesh says Pakistan
defense minister said has said just said
there is nothing like the LOC as the
Shimla agreement is scrapped. It's just
a ceasefire now. What does it mean? Is
it good? It's nothing. It's it's just
redefining what it is. So before the
Shimla agreement, the LOC was called the
ceasefire
line. So now the Pakistan defense
minister is saying that it's the LOC now
should be called the ceasefire line
because the Shimla agreement is
scrapped. The Pakistanis never respected
the Shimla agreement anyway. So it it
means nothing. We don't care about it.
Pakistan is insignificant and if they
try something, we're going to respond
militarily. That's all they have to
remember. That's all.
So it's fine. Akar says, "Why is Japan
offering its
IHIXF91 engine for co-development and
local production for our AMCA? How does
it benefit them?" Looks too good to be
true. If it looks too big too good to be
true, it probably is. See, Japan
unfortunately is under the control of
the US, especially when it comes to uh
military technology and so on so forth.
So if something is being offered to us,
think of it possibly as an American
Trojan horse.
How does it benefit them? Maybe there
will be some components in the
technology that could be eventually used
to disable our aircraft in the future.
And it's not Japan that's doing it, but
the US because the US controls Japan.
So, one has to be very
wary of these
things. Uh, kids bedtime stories says
why does the Modi government continue to
deny there's been increased Chinese
occupation of India in recent times?
There's clear proof. Well, I haven't
seen this myself. I haven't seen the
clear proof myself.
Do you have the access to the latest
Maxar satellite imagery? Maybe the print
or the squint or the wire or the fire
has put something out? I'm not sure.
Maybe it's true, maybe it's not true. I
don't know what it is. Um increased
Chinese occupation. How many? Like how
much is it like a 100 square kilometers,
200, 500,000 or 20 square kilm? What
exactly is it? I'm not sure. And even if
something like this has happened, why
should the government go and make it
public? It's a national security matter.
Why don't we support our
government? I don't get it. I personally
have not seen the proof. Maybe there is
proof. You can put in the comments.
Okay? I I I promise you I will look into
it and if it's the case, I I'll agree
there's proof if it is genuinely there.
I kind of have an understanding of how
to scrutinize proof and to discern what
is fake proof from real proof. I I think
I have the experience and knowledge to
do that. So in case it is there, please
put the link sir in the dis in in the
comments once this live stream is over.
I will I promise you check it out. All
right. Thank you, sir. Thank you. Uh
Grock says, "I heard about crown
council committee of 300s." 300. What's
the
history? Now these I haven't read this
history. I'm sorry. Crown Council
Committee of 300. This sounds like what
some people would call what do they call
it? Like I don't know. I'm not sure what
this is. I I've I've heard of it
vaguely. I haven't studied the
history. So unfortunately I won't be
able to answer your question. Crown
Council Committee of 300. Sounds like
some kind of vague shady story about
some kind of alternative history or
maybe hidden history, but I'm not sure
what it is.
Uh Samir says, "Is watching cricket a
luxury view on RCB stampede?" Watching
cricket is not a luxury. It's something
everybody does. And of course, if you
spend a lot of time watching it, it's a
luxury because time is the most
important and valuable commodity
commodity in your life. And if you spend
a lot of your time watching cricket,
yeah, you're spending your most valuable
asset uh essentially doing nothing. You
can watch once in a while. You can watch
highlights. You can even watch an IPL
match three four hours. But if you watch
it on a regular basis, yeah, views on
RCB stampede. Very unfortunate. Very
unfortunate. Sad. Sad.
Terrible. Milin says, "Opinion on Poland
for rejecting illegals." What's the
word? Based right thing to do. Good job.
Jurgen says, "Entire Europe is in the
verge of collapse because of demographic
changes and Islamic immigration. What's
the future of Europe? Will it be a new
headache for the entire world after the
Middle East crisis?" Love you S. Thank
you, S. Thank you so much, Sar. uh I
don't think the whole of Europe is on
the verge of collapse but many countries
are under tremendous strain and some
could be on eventually going to be on
the verge of complete demographic
makeover because of the the policy
that's been pushed over into these
nations by Brussels of of forcing them
to accept illegal immigrants or making
perhaps making it legal but only
military age men from certain places and
so on. It's terrible. It looks like the
future of Europe is is not good based on
what's
happening. Will it be a new headache for
the whole world after the Middle East
crisis? I hope not. I don't think it's
going to be a new headache thus far.
These things take take time to happen.
Maybe Europe will be the headache in 30,
40, 50 years, but not not
immediately,
right? Okay. I think we have covered
everything as far as I can. It's almost
one and a half hours. I was supposed to
do a 1 hour live stream. So, um yeah,
that's this is the end for today's live
stream. Thank you so much everybody for
watching. I really really appreciate all
of
you. And uh the next live stream will be
on Saturday. It'll be a regular Ask a
Widget live stream. And uh yeah, I look
forward to seeing you all over there.
And next week I'm I will continue with
the Geost Strategy podcast as well as
the Indian Interest Podcast. It's going
to be a regular recurring feature on the
channel going forward. I hope it gives
you some value. I hope it is very
different from anything you have seen in
the Indian or maybe global scene. All
right. Thank you so much everybody.
Please keep learning. Please keep asking
questions. And uh yeah, there's one more
question. Strangely Proton, how are you
also able to do? How are you also do you
work these days? I work on my own. I am
happily unemployed or self-employed.
Okay? I don't work for anybody. It's
been a while and I'm very
happy with my current
uh status. So, thank you so much
everybody. Keep asking questions. Keep
raising your standards. Keep learning
and I will see you in the next next live
stream. Thank you so much. Bye-bye.